I'm sorry for having called you out.
Here.
It is from Edward Elric.
A bill?
Hospital charges,
as well as doctor's fees,
food expenses while in the hospital, and so on.
All to be paid for by the
Eastern Command Center.
Snack food charges?
Reading materials charges...
As well as a large bill
from a toy store...
Where are they?
They have left on a trip
to further their objective.
I believe they will contact us before long,
so for the time being...
I asked you where they were!
Colonel...
Look at this.
Are the Elric brothers here?!
No, they aren't.
Where have they gone?
Eh, um, well...
Hey...
Oh! Nice going, dear.
Let's go.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
We're finally here! Rush Valley!
How pretty!
That ring is the new model from Studio Remis!
Who would have thought I'd be laying eyes on it in this town?
Buy it, buy it!
You bet, honey!
How pretty!
This Automail is the 1911 Gods' model!
Who would've thought the day would come when I'd be able to behold it!
How nice! I sure would like it!
That sure is nice.
Let me put it on!
No way.
Why not?
A culverin cannon is
made for men's ideals.
A girl like you doesn't need one.
Well, well, what a shabby little store this is.
Pops, let me have the
strongest thing you've got.
I've come into some easy money, and I'm going to blow it all!
You don't ignore a customer, you know!
Oh, what's that?
Fine little piece, isn't it?
Stick it on me, would you?
Can't do that.
I only give my Automail to people who really need it.
You what?! I'm a customer here!
You don't need something like this, do you?
Wh-What's with you,
you nasty old man?
Who needs your broken-down Automail, anyway?
You hack mechanic!
Come on! Come on! It's what Rush Valley is famous for!
Automail arm wrestling!
Entrance fee is 10,000 cens! Beat the champion,
and you win all the money collected so far!
Come and take it, you thieves!
Pardon us.
All right! I'll step up to the plate!
Oh, way to go, mister!
You're sure fired up!
Are you ready?
Ready... Fight!
Huh?
Brother, did you see that just now?
Yeah.
Ready...
Fight!
There's nothing they could do, huh?
Little lady, are you sure you're okay with that substandard rig of yours?
Hey, this is crazy!
After all,
she's using that old fart's Automail!
Are you ready?
Ready...
Fight!
Too bad!
If you like, I can introduce you
to an able craftsman.
So, are there any challengers who want to go next?
Oh!
The strong-looking gentleman there! How about going a round?
Huh, me?
No, that's okay.
Is that so? Well, how about the—
or so I thought,
but calling out such a bean sprout of a boy wouldn't be right of me.
Don't call me a bean sprout!
Ooh, he's got a lot of energy for a bean sprout, huh?
Although, his Automail is awfully shoddy.
Al, let Ed go.
Huh?
Okay...
Ed! Don't you dare lose to him!
Okay then, let's go.
Ready...
Fight!
Sorry about that.
The scrap collectors are going to be really busy today.
Neener neener!
510,000 cens!
With this much, I can buy
all of those parts that I wanted!
But...
what I'm really happy about is...
What?
Nothing.
You're the guys who were just...
You really did a number
on us back there.
Unless you want to get hurt,
hand over that money quietly!
What's your problem?!
We beat you fair and square for it!
Shut up!
That bean sprout obviously cheated!
What about you?!
You used alchemy, didn't you?!
You used it too, didn't you?!
Ed, did you use alchemy?
Yeah.
Al, you knew about it?
Hm? Uh-huh.
Is that right?
Ed...
Yeah?
Winry!
Yow-ow-ow...
That hurt! What are you doing, Win—
Brother!
Ed, you dummy!
Colonel,
I've brought Major Armstrong.
To be sure,
there are those whom we suspect were
the ones who killed the Brigadier General.
In that case, why haven't
you arrested them at once?
They are suspected,
but we don't know who they are.
Give me the details.
I cannot.
As a colonel,
I am instructing you to tell me!
I cannot say.
That's enough. Go.
That's strange, huh?
No.
He said those whom we suspect
were the ones who killed Hughes,
which means there was more than one of them.
If he wouldn't answer me,
even when I ordered him to as a colonel,
it means that someone with a rank higher than mine
has forbidden the Major
to talk about it.
Furthermore, like Lieutenant Ross said,
since the Elric brothers are taking independent action
without reporting to me first,
we have to consider that the military is involved with the Philosopher's Stone somehow.
That couldn't be...!
As it is, we're in the dark.
Winry's nowhere to be found, huh?
Maybe it was a bad idea to use alchemy when you were arm wrestling.
Those guys were cheating, you know.
That may be so...
Did you hurt your arm?
I saw you at the
arm wrestling competition.
Mind if I sit next to you?
No.
Are your legs Automail, too?
Mm-hmm.
I'm surprised you could tell.
I'm an artificial-limb outfitter myself.
You hurt your arm, right?
Ah, mm-hmm.
Let me see.
Incredible. The working is
simple yet high-performance.
There's nothing wasted in this design.
There's a load on
your suspension here.
Looks like you've bent a cylinder.
You can tell that quickly
just by looking?
Whoever made this
has incredible skill.
You should have them
take a look at this right away.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Say, how did you
come to have Automail?
I was in a train accident.
And he's the one?
Mm-hmm.
He took me in and even gave me
an arm and a pair of legs. Dominic-san.
In that case, shouldn't you have him
fix you up all the more?
I should, I suppose.
Why don't you ask him?
I don't want to tell him that
I lost the arm wrestling contest.
You see, I...
I wanted to prove that
his Automail was amazing.
But then...
I know!
So then, all you need to do is show that your Automail is amazing, right?
Uh-huh...
But how?
You know what?
You could show that your Automail is amazing
by beating a State Alchemist who also has Automail, couldn't you?
You might be right, but...
Let me take care of that.
Okay.
Paninya, what are you doing there?
D-Dominic-san...
S-Sorry to intrude. I'm Winry Rockbell,
an Automail mechanic from Resembool.
Rockbell from Resembool?!
D-Don't tell me you're Pinako's...!
The leopardess of Resembool!
Just thinking about her horrifies me!
Are you an acquaintance
of my grandma?
Don't be ridiculous!
What's the matter with your arm?
N-Nothing much.
Do as you will.
Jeez, where is that Winry?
I wonder if she slept outside.
Hey!
I finally found you!
You dumb jerk, that's my line!
Sorry! I flew off
the handle yesterday.
Good morning!
You were there when
we were arm wrestling...
Her name's Paninya.
I stayed over at
her house last night.
Is that right?
Say, Ed...
What's up?
Can I take a look at
your silver watch?
What's this about,
all of a sudden?
Please?
For the love of...
Here.
I'll take this!
What the! Hey!
It's a contest, Ed!
If you can get your silver watch back before Paninya takes it to the pawn shop, you win!
Pipsqueak, come on up here!
Hey!
Winry!
If you don't give chase quickly, you can kiss your watch good-bye, Mr.
Alchemist.
Brother!
Winry, why would you
do such a thing?
I want Ed to say
that her Automail is amazing.
Hold it!
Wait the hell up!
You're hanging in there pretty well, aren't you?
You bet I am!
Just like a cat!
Why, you!
How about you use that
trademark alchemy of yours?
Stop jerking me around!
Uh-oh...
Now, how about
returning my silver watch?
Take this! My 1.5-inch culverin cannon!
What?!
Maybe they're going too far.
Brother!
I wonder if he's okay.
Let's see...
The pawn shop...
This is mine!
Why, you!
Yow-ow-ow-ow...
Are you okay?
And I was so close, too...
I don't know what your reasons are,
but I can't let anyone beat me
when it comes to my Automail.
Aww! And here, all I wanted to do was show Dominic-san how amazing his Automail is.
It was plenty amazing.
For crying out loud,
you stupid little girl...
Good day.
I don't need you
to do that for me.
But...
Listen, your Automail isn't just some device.
They're your very limbs.
And they're yours alone.
I don't remember raising any daughters who weren't aware of such a thing.
I get it.
You make your Automail with the person in mind.
It becomes a part of that
person's body, doesn't it?
Now that you mention it,
I guess I was glad when I was able to
stand on my own two feet once again.
Please, Colonel,
if you can, locate the criminal who
did that to Brigadier General Hughes!
I'll do anything!
The investigation concerning his death in the line of duty
has already been suspended.
Which is why I'm asking you, Colonel!
Working hard as usual, eh, Mustang-kun?
It's been too long, General Hakuro.
I heard the rumors that you were being relocated to Central.
However, that doesn't necessarily mean it won't be overruled.
If I could ask for your support, I will serve you to my fullest.
I humbly look forward
to your guidance.
That's the right attitude.
Excuse me!
I'm heading upward.
Will you come with me?
You need to ask,
after all this time?
Well then, if you'll excuse us...
Yeah.
Give Winry our best.
Ed, are you asleep?
No.
Say, I noticed earlier that it looks like you've gotten surprisingly taller.
Course I have.
Which means that before long, I'll need to get a new arm and leg ready for you.
How about it? Why don't
we go back to Resembool?
I dunno...
Actually, I'm okay for now.
How come?
Is it that you simply
don't want Automail?
I'll do my best.
I'll study harder and harder,
to keep you from being handicapped for the rest of your life.
So...
So please...
Winry...
Even so,
we want to get our bodies back.
It's something we have
to do for ourselves.
Bad news, Brother!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 27: "Sensei"
Forgive us, Sensei,
for what we did to our mother.